(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-03T22:59:07.985173",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
1st generation 電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言
[1st Generation: Cyber Pure Oshi Grand Declaration]
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！
[Hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!]
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！
[Hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!]
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！
[Hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!]
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！
[Hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!]
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！
[Hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!]
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！
[Hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!]
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！
[Hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!]
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！
[Hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!]
1st generation 電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言
[1st Generation: Cyber Pure Oshi Grand Declaration]
月夜のセレナーデ
A moonlit night's serenade
白い薔薇は誰を想う
Who does the white rose yearn for?
その身を滅ぼさせて
Destroying its own self...
愛を歌うの
...it sings of love.
こぼれ落ちた花びらが
The spilled petals...
寂しさの跡を隠した
...hid the traces of loneliness.
ねぇ早く迎えに来て
Hey, come to rescue me quickly.
最後の1片が落ちるその前に
Before the very last petal falls.
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Right now, I won't flock with any other flower.
あなただけを待っている
I am waiting only for you.
あなたとならこの身体が
If it's with you, even if this body...
壊されたってもう構わない
...is destroyed, I don't care anymore.
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
If you touch my thorns, you will get hurt.
その覚悟がないなら
If you don't have that determination...
いっそここから消えてよ
...then just disappear from here already.
重く閉ざした
Heavily locked away...
so Secret Garden
夜風はリゾルート
The night wind is resolute.
白い薔薇は覚醒する
The white rose awakens.
背中押されるように
As if pushed from behind,
扉開いた
the door has opened.
ただ一人で枯れていくの
To just wither away all alone...
待ってるだけじゃいられない
...I cannot just stay and wait.
衝動の赴くまま
Driven by pure impulse,
茨の道を裸足で駆け抜けていく
I run through the thorny path barefoot.
凛と咲き誇る花でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming with dignity.
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you,
逢いに行くの どんなに遠く
I'll go to meet you, no matter how far,
離れていても見つけ出せる
even if we are apart, I can find you.
暗い世界も怖くない
Even a dark world is not scary,
あなたを感じるから
because I feel you.
すべて失ったっていい
I don't mind losing everything.
二度と戻らない
Never to return...
so Secret Garden
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Right now, I won't flock with any other flower.
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you.
かすみ草が私を呼ぶ
The baby's breath calls out to me.
鮮やかに燃える強気薔薇
A strong rose burning brilliantly.
凛と咲き誇る花でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming with dignity.
やっとここで出会えた
At last, we met here.
あなたとならこの身体が
If it's with you, even if this body...
壊されたってもう構わない
...is destroyed, I don't care anymore.
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
If you touch my thorns, you will get hurt.
その覚悟があるのね
But you have that determination, don't you?
手を取り合えば広がる
If we take each other's hands, it will unfold—
誰も知らない
—a world no one knows...
so sacred universe
イェーイ！
Yay!
終わりましたー！
And that's the end of the song!
始まりましたー！
Here we go!
イェーイ！
Yay!
さてさて じゃあちょっとね
Alright, now that we've...
Secret Garden歌った後なんですけども
...finished singing "Secret Garden"...
まずは自己紹介！
...let's start with our introductions!
7年目の自己紹介！
Introductions for our 7th year!
イェーイ！
Yay!
やっていきますかね じゃあ アキロゼから！
Let's do this! Starting with Akirose!
はーい！
Okay!
えー 7年目の自己紹介行きます！
I'll do my 7th-year introduction!
ホロライブ1期生の癒し系ハーフエルフ
Hololive 1st Gen's healing half-elf...
アキロゼことアキ・ローゼンタールです！
...Aki Rosenthal, also known as Akirose!
ハロハロハロー！ アローナ！
Hello, hello, hello! Alona!
アローナ！
Alona!
いつもシンプル！
Always simple!
これ、どこ行ったんだ？
Where did this go?
置いてけ、置いてけ！
Leave it, leave it!
明るくなった？
Did it get brighter?
やめてくれ！みんながいる中で、最近自己紹介するの恥ずかしくなっちゃって...
Stop it! In front of everyone, I've recently started feeling embarrassed doing self-introductions...
恥を捨てろ！/ 無理無理無理！そんな恥を捨てたはーちゃま！
Throw away your shame! / No way! Here's Haachama, who threw away her shame!
はーちゃまっちゃまー！
Haachamachama!
ワールドアイドル最強アイドル、はーちゃまこと赤井はあとです！
World's strongest idol, Red Heart aka Haachama!
イェーイ！おすおす！
Yay! Cheers!
そして！
And then!
はーい！ホロライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル、夏色まつりです！
Hi! Hololive's purity representative, everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri!
7年目も清楚でやっていくぜ！
I'll keep being pure even in my 7th year!
清楚？ちょっと聞こえない...
Pure? I can't really hear you...
最近ね、最近だいぶ落ち着きを取り戻し...
Lately, I've calmed down quite a lot...
はい、ということでね。1曲目、「Secret Garden」だったんですが。
So, the first song was "Secret Garden".
去年の周年で発表したオリ曲ということで、あれから1年経ちました！
It was the original song announced at last year's anniversary. It's been a year!
早い！あの楽曲からもう1年？
So fast! A whole year since that song?
いや、早いねー！あっという間だね、本当に秒すぎる！
Wow, that's fast! In the blink of an eye, it went by in seconds!
今回はオープニングとして歌わせていただきましたけど、
We got to sing it as our opening song this time,
今年はオリ曲どうなんですか？はーちゃん
but how about this year's original song, Haachama?
どうなんだろうねー？あるのかなー？
I wonder? Is there one?
さあそしてそして、なにやらステージが... 見てくださいよ！
And then, look at the stage!
今回のステージはなんと、バーチャル世界の秋葉原をイメージして、
This stage is modeled after virtual Akihabara,
VTuberならではのデジタル感とか、あとはちょっと推し活感みたいなね、雰囲気もあって...
with a digital feel unique to VTubers, and also an "oshi-katsu" vibe...
YAGO！YAGOやめて！
YAGO! Stop with the YAGO!
1号、2号ってあるし！
There's No. 1 and No. 2!
もろじゃねーかよ！
It's totally obvious!
でも、みんなのいろんな思い出のものが、いろんなところに散りばめられてるんだよね！
But everyone's memories are scattered all over!
とってもかっこよくて可愛いイメージとなっておりますので、そちらも楽しんでください！
It has a really cool and cute look, so please look forward to that too!
そしてさらに！今回のハッシュタグは... こちら！
And furthermore! This time's hashtag is... this!
電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言！
Dennou Pure Oshi Grand Declaration!
感想をいっぱいXでポストしてね！
Please post lots of your thoughts on X!
ちなみに、このハッシュタグですが、なんでこの名前かは、
By the way, as for why this hashtag has this name...
最後まで見てくれたら、その秘密がわかっちゃうかもしれません！
If you watch until the end, that secret might be revealed!
わからなかった場合はどうしたらいいですか？
What if we don't find out?
はーちゃんが責任を取る！何でもする！
Haachama will take responsibility! I'll do anything!
何でもする？！やばいやばい！ということで、みんなでいろいろ歌っていきたいんですが...
Anything?! That's crazy! So, we want to sing various songs...
まずはですね、ソロパートからやっていこうと思います！
First, we'll start with the solo parts!
ソロの順番はもう発表しちゃいますか。
Shall we announce the solo order now?
1曲目歌う人！はーい！まつりちゃん！
First singer! Me! Matsurichan!
まつりちゃんのソロはどんな感じなんですか？ / この雰囲気に合った曲を選んだんで、楽しみにしててください。
What's your solo like? / I chose a song that fits this atmosphere, so look forward to it.
そしてその次は？
And after that?
はーい！はーちゃまはもりもりでいきますので、お楽しみに！新しい曲もある！
Me! Haachama will go all out, so look forward to it! There's also a new song!
そしてその次が？ / はーい！
And next? / Me!
この空間にぴったりで、新世界みたいな、地球みたいなでかい感じでいかせていただきます！
It's perfect for this space, like a new world, with a huge Earth-like feel!
最後は白上ですが、本当に自分の好きな楽曲を歌わせていただく予定でございます！
Lastly, Fubuki plans to sing her absolute favorite songs!
トップバッターとして、まつりちゃんいかせていただきますよ！それではいきましょう、どうぞ！
As the first performer, Matsurichan is going! Here we go, please enjoy!
アンハッピー？
Unhappy?
アンラッキー？
Unlucky?
人ならざるものも
Even those who aren't human,
BEE HAPPY！
BEE HAPPY!
抱まず目指せよ 生きていんだし
aim forward without hesitation, since we're alive.
目を逸らした過去も
Even the past you turned away from,
退屈な未来も
and even the boring future,
カウンセリング やれやれ
counseling, oh boy...
ぽんこつかい？ ピースピース
Are you a klutz? Peace peace!
ねねね、何だかどうして
Hey hey, why is it somehow...
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting somehow
触れられない 触れたくもない
Unreachable, untouchable
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と
With my past self, self, self, self
もうとっくに死んでる
Who's already long dead
透明な亡霊と対決
Facing off with a transparent ghost
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep inside innocent, painful memories
残念？ もう居ないのに
What a shame? Even though they're no longer here
あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Oh? Is that better? How ironic
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it my current self that is transparent?
ナンセンス
Nonsense
消えないレッテル
An indelible label
Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Yes! In short, a complex
取り憑かれているみたい
It's like I'm haunted
巻き付いたまま
Still wrapped around me,
まだ離れない
still unwilling to leave
在りし日の自分
My former self
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない
Not dead yet
お前と前の連鎖
The chain of you and the past
生きていることは変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep changing
不幸に甘んじて
Resigned to unhappiness,
満足するのよ
you find satisfaction in it
幸せになろうとしないなんて傲慢だ
How arrogant to not even try to be happy
この世はこの世は 奇奇怪怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Will it be a demon or a snake next?
出会って会ってやっと始まる物語
A story that finally begins when we meet
さあ人が化物か
So, is it human or monster?
閑話休題ピースピース
But digression aside, peace, peace
Past & Future can't change the Past
Past & Future run for the Future
カットイン
Cut-in!
何だかどうして未来になんの何の希望もない期待出来ない
For some reason, I can't expect any hope for the future
ような気がして
I feel like...
もう随分生きている
I've been living for a long time
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Fed up with déjà vu and clichés
素敵な出来事の気配もない
There's no sign of anything wonderful happening
散々積んだ経験の因果
The karma of so much accumulated experience
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
A hollowed-out myth and a boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I want stimulation
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I'm bored with it, I'm used to it
なんて
Just kidding...
整っていくガイダンス
The guidance coming together
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance
蓋されていくみたい
It's like being sealed up
吸い尽くして
Suck it dry
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
This, that, and everything tastes the same
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない
Not dead yet
お前と前の連鎖
The chain of you and the past
いつの世も過去も未来も今にあるんだ
In any age, the past and the future are in the present
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill your life with honest devotion
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない
Not dead yet
お前に行っているんだ
I'm talking to you
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であれ
Don't give up on happiness, remain human
ただ苦しみに慣れて
Just getting used to suffering
耐えているだけじゃ
and just enduring it
死んでいるのと同然
is the same as being dead
屍のアンデッド
A corpse-like undead
UNHAPPY?
悩める人の子よ
O troubled child of man
UNLUCKY?
人成らざる者も
Even those who aren't human
BE HAPPY!
弛まず目指せよ
Aim for it tirelessly
生きているんだし
Since you're alive
不幸に浸るな
Don't wallow in unhappiness
幸せになるのも
Becoming happy...
どうせなら全部お前が選べよ
You might as well choose it all yourself
古今東西
All times and places
一切合切森羅万象 ピースピース
All of creation, lock, stock, and barrel, peace, peace
Past & Future can't change the Past
Past & Future run for the Future
人の在る所に
Wherever people exist,
いつも憂い事
there is always sorrow
生き抜け 化物ばかりの物語
Survive through this story full of monsters
清く 正しく 美しく
Pure, righteous, and beautiful.
8年目からは、キレイな赤井はあとに戻ることを
From my eighth year, to return to being a clean Akai Haato,
私は誓います！
I so swear!
なーんて言うと思ったかー！
Like I'd ever say that!
行くぞ、お前ら！
Let's go, everyone!
10周年まで一人も欠けずに、止まんないよ！
Don't stop till our 10th anniversary, let's keep everyone together!
行っくぞー！
Here we go!
Good god!
I just wanna live honestly
雑音ばかり
Nothing but noise
That's alright, I'm gonna go my way, leave me
Don't change your mind
Every time I say "No"
静観してなよ 優等生は
Just sit back and watch, you model student
Fake up 正義の味方
Fake up, ally of justice
It's true of world, isn't it?
You must be good
Do as I told
(Please, please)
I'm sick of hearing
your words
I ain't so good girl
Never be lap dog
You
正論”的”なのもういいって
I've had enough of your "sound arguments"
「物語に必要」と
Saying "It's necessary for the story"
そこまで言うのなら演じ切ってやるわ
If you go that far, I'll play the part perfectly
いい子ちゃんのまま
as a good little girl
Yes, yes, yes, No, No, No
Who is the Villain?
だって I'm a Hero, right? right? right?
Because I'm a Hero, right, right, right?
イヤになるわ
I'm sick of it
誰が正義なんて
Who decided
決めたのかしらね
what justice is?
Oh, well
(Who? x 5)
もうどっちだってそういい子ちゃんのままじゃ
Either way, if I just stay a good little girl...
はい、ちゃんちゃん！
That's all, folks!
Yeah!
Who is the Villain?
Who?
One, two, three, go!
I give you my big RED HEART
My my big RED HEART
I'll be true to my RED HEART
I give you my big RED HEART
My my RED HEART
Big RED HEART
I'll be true to my RED HEART
My my big RED HEART
いっただっきまーす♡
Bon appétit!
トントカトン！ トントカトン！
Chop-chop-chop! Chop-chop-chop!
お肉と野菜をトントカトン☆
Chop the meat and veggies, chop-chop-chop!
サフリンパッ！ サフリンパッ！
Sizzle-sizzle! Sizzle-sizzle!
カラピッチュ！ 揚げ物だって出来ちゃいます！
Crispy-crisp! I can even make deep-fried food!
ぐとぅぐとぅ とっぷすとっぷす タラリンチュラリン エビのアジ！
Bubbly-bubble, drip-drop-drip! Shrimp-flavored magic!
はあちゃまクッキング！
Haachama Cooking!
はーじまっちゃまーー！
Is starting!
1. 調べない
1. Don't look things up!
調べた奴からサフリンパ！
Anyone who looks up a recipe gets sizzled!
ネットやレシピを見るのは ダメダメ
Looking up things online or in recipes is forbidden!
2. 計らない
2. Don't measure!
計るのなんてゴミ！
Measuring is trash!
目分量でも作れるのが 一流だろぉぉお！
Being able to cook by estimation is what makes you top-tier!
3. はちゃめちゃアレンジ！
3. Crazy improvisations!
最後はオリジナルの隠し味
Finishing with a unique secret ingredient!
これは料理の成長物語...！
This is a tale of culinary growth!
はあちゃまカレーは5つ星☆☆☆☆☆
Haachama Curry is five-star!
スパイスマシマシで！
With extra, extra spices!
作り方を今教えます
I will now teach you how to make it.
めんどくさいので省きます！
It's too much hassle, so I'll skip it!
（てめぇで勝手に創りだせ！）
(Create it yourself, damn it!)
見た目はゴミ！ でもめちゃ美味い！
It looks like garbage! But it tastes amazing!
目指すは世界一！
Aiming to be the best in the world!
あなたの胃袋掴んじゃう
I'm gonna win over your stomach!
ぎゅっ ぎゅっ ぎゅっ ぎゅっ
Squeeze, squeeze, squeeze, squeeze...
はい、あーん♡
Open wide, say ahh!
友達 減る 見せたら 減る
Lose friends! Show them this and you'll lose them!
左から2番目に 漂う正気
Sanity drifts second from the left...
正気で美味しい 完全食♡
Sanity-shattering delicious complete food!
お残しした人だあれ？
Who left leftovers on their plate?
BAN！ はい！ BAN！ はい！
Banned! Yes! Banned! Yes!
おつるーじゅ！
Otsuruuju!
It's only love
もしも願い一つだけ
If one of my wishes
叶うなら
were to come true
キミのそばで眠らせて
Let me sleep by your side,
どんな場所でもいいよ
anywhere will do.
Beautiful World
迷わずにキミだけを 見つめている
Without losing sight, I'm looking only at you.
Beautiful Boy
自分の美しさ
You still don't know
まだ知らないの
your own beauty.
It's only love
寝ても覚めても
Whether awake or asleep,
少年マンガ
like a boy's manga,
夢見てばっか
simply dreaming.
自分が好きじゃないの
You don't like yourself, do you?
何が欲しいか 分からなくて
Not knowing what you want,
ただ欲しがって ヌルイ涙が
simply wanting, lukewarm tears
頬を伝う
run down your cheek.
言いたいことなんか無い
There's nothing I want to say,
ただもう一度会いたい
I just want to meet you once again.
言いたいこと言えない
Unable to say what I want to say,
根性なし かもしれない
perhaps I'm just spineless...
それでもいいけど
But that's fine too.
もしも願い一つだけ
If one of my wishes
叶うなら
were to come true,
キミのそばで眠らせて
let me sleep by your side,
どんな場所でもいいよ
anywhere will do.
Beautiful World
迷わずにキミだけを 見つめている
Without losing sight, I'm looking only at you.
Beautiful Boy
自分の美しさ
You still don't know
まだ知らないの
your own beauty.
It's only love
どんなことでもやってみて
Try doing whatever it is,
損したって
even if you lose out,
少し経験値上がる
your experience points will go up a bit.
新聞なんていらない
I don't need a newspaper,
肝心なことが載ってない
it doesn't cover the things that really matter.
最近調子どうdai？
How've you been doing lately?
元気にしてるなら
If you're doing well,
別にいいけど
then that's all that matters.
僕の世界消えるまで
Until my world vanishes,
会えぬなら
if I can't meet you,
キミのそばで眠らせて
let me sleep by your side,
どんな場所でも結構
anywhere will do.
Beautiful World
儚く過ぎていく 日々の中で
In these fleeting days that pass us by,
Beautiful Boy
僕らは知り合いじゃないの
we're not even acquaintances...
もしも願いひとつだけ
If only one wish of mine...
叶うなら
...could come true,
君のそばで眠らせて
let me sleep by your side.
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
桜のあと (all quartets lead to the?)
After the Cherry Blossoms (all quartets lead to the?)
All quartets lead, lead to...? say la-la-la...
やあ、また会えたね
Hey, we meet again,
こんばんは、いやこんにちはだっけ？
good evening... or is it good afternoon?
広いようで狭いようで
It seems wide, yet so narrow,
退屈は要らないみたいだね
so it looks like we won't need boredom.
あぁ、問題は依然あって
Ah, the problems are still there,
頭痛いんだけど
giving me a headache,
少しずつって言い聞かせて
but I tell myself to take it step by step,
願い事かなえていきましょうね
so let's make our wishes come true!
I shall remember I wanna do
I shall remember
拾い集めた後悔のかけらたちを
Gathering the fragments of our regrets,
夜が明ける前に
before the night breaks into dawn,
ラベルを貼って並べてって
I'll label them and line them up,
希望に変える準備を継続中
and keep preparing to turn them into hope!
桜が咲いて散ったその後で何が真実なのかは
After the cherry blossoms bloom and fall, what is truly real?
わかるから future melody
Because I understand, future melody,
そう、今は奏でて
yes, play it now.
愛だ世界救うだなんて僕は信じてないけどね
I don't believe in things like love saving the world, but...
今 目の前の君が
right now, I want you right in front of me
明日を生きられるくらいには
to at least be able to live through tomorrow.
ありえない不条理はぶっ飛ばしていけ
So kick away all that ridiculous absurdity!
ウィスキー炭酸、余す必要ないよ
Whiskey and soda water, no need to leave any behind,
嘘つき
you liar!
さあ アンプリファーは絶好調
Now, the amplifier is in perfect shape,
エレキギターがうねってる
the electric guitar is roaring.
こんなにもさ、歪んでるのに
Even though it's distorted like this,
心が純粋に求めてる
my heart is purely yearning for it.
あぁ 何回も何千回も
Ah, over and over, thousands of times,
お望み通り鳴らすよ
I'll play it just as you wish.
君が欲しいタイミングで
At the moment you want it,
わがままにスイッチを押しましょうか
shall we selfishly push the switch?
You can reaction, and play it loud
You can reaction
はしゃぎ過ぎてた青春時代のいろはとか
The basics of our youth when we was running wild...
ホコリ被る前に
before they gather dust,
選び出して磨いてって
choose them and polish them up.
歌に乗っちゃう番狂わせしたい
I want to pull off an upset riding on this song!
一斉のせで魔法も使えるよ
On the count of three, we can even use magic,
君は自由なんだから
because you are free.
止めないで future symphony
Don't stop, future symphony,
そう、お気に召すまま
yes, just as you like.
不器用でも混ぜ合わせるよ この街に響いていけ
Even if clumsy, we'll mix it together, so let it echo through this city!
ミュージック 歪なるミュージック
Music, distorted music,
大丈夫 僕らが試金石
it's alright, we are the touchstone.
ジャジャジャジャーン、足りない！キック、リズムを打て！
Dun-dun-dun-dun, not enough! Kick, hit the rhythm!
ベース＆ギター
Bass and guitar,
おまけに僕が歌えば四重奏
plus me singing makes it a quartet!
I shall remember I wanna do
忘れない、忘れないよ
I won't forget, I won't forget,
今夜大人になっても
even if I become an adult tonight.
だからこの瞬間は楽しませて
So let me enjoy this very moment.
歌うよ、でたらめでいいよね？
I'm going to sing, nonsense is fine, right?
All quartets lead, lead to...? say la-la-la...
la-la-la-la-la...
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la...
桜が 桜が
The cherry blossoms, the cherry blossoms...
咲いて散ったその後で 何が真実なのかは
...bloomed and scattered. What is truly real...
わかるから future melody そう 今は奏でて
...I'll understand, so play that future melody now.
愛だ世界救うだなんて 僕は信じてないけどね
I don't really believe in things like love or saving the world,
今 目の前の君が 明日を生きられるくらいには
but at least enough so that you, right before me, can live through tomorrow...
ありえない不条理はぶっ飛ばしていけ
...I will blow away any impossible absurdity!
with 喜怒哀楽 余すな全部 惜しみもなく
With all emotions, leave nothing behind, unsparingly.
言えないまま 飲み込むなんて事はよして
Stop swallowing down your words unspoken.
with 喜怒哀楽 大丈夫さ どこまでも行くだろう
With all emotions, we'll be fine. We can go anywhere.
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la-la-la...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
おっしゃ！ということで、ソロパートでしたー！
Alright! And with that, that was my solo part!
あれ？みんな？お着替えしてたよね、一緒に今？
Huh? Everyone? Weren't you changing just now?
何その動き？何その動き？怖っ！
What are those moves? What are those moves? Scary!
え、何何何何！どうした、みんな？
Wait, what, what, what, what! What's wrong, everyone?
なんかついていってたの？ちゃんと見てくれてた？
Were you following along? Were you watching closely?
ずっと一緒にいたよ。
We were with you the whole time.
ずっとそこにいたよ。どこにいたんだっけ？
We were right there. Wait, where were we again?
一番近くで見てた。
We watched from the closest spot.
え、一番近くで見てた！？
Huh, from the closest spot?!
そうだよ！
That's right!
なんか、確かに今日多いなとか思ったけど...
Yeah, I did think there was a lot of us today...
はい、ということで、ソロパートだったんですけども、一人ずつね、改めて感想などなど…まつりちゃんのアンデッド！
Alright, so that was my solo part, but let's go around and share our thoughts... Starting with Matsuri-chan's Undead!
はい！アンデッドね、やっぱこの雰囲気に合わせて選んだんですけど、なんかこの歌詞が、すごいMVっぽく出してもらってね！
Yes! I chose Undead to match this atmosphere, and they displayed the lyrics like in a music video!
めっちゃよかった！
It was so good!
そうなんですよ！かっこかわいく歌えたかなと思います。そして、はあちゃん！
I know! I think I managed to sing it both cool and cute. And next, Haato-chan!
はーい！はあちゃんと一緒に踊りました！
Yes! You danced along with Haato!
はあとやばかった！
Haato was amazing!
そして、新しく出たね、めちょごみ完全色！みんなどうだった？
And my newly released cover, 'Mechogomi Kanzenshoku'! How was it, everyone?
よかったよー！
It was awesome!
これ、実写版が入ってたもんね！
It even had those live-action clips!
そしてアキちゃん！
And next, Aki-chan!
はーい！アキロゼは、ラブドッキュンね！
Yes! AkiRoze did 'Love Dokkyun'!
いやー、結構ね、頑張らせてもらったんだけど...
Man, I really worked quite hard on that one...
この空間でね、こういう演出をずーっとずーっとやりたいなと思ってたから、ちょうどね、世界観にも合ってるし、すごく頑張りました！
I've always, always wanted to do a performance like that in this kind of space. It fits the vibe perfectly, so I put my all into it!
さすがだったよー！
You were superb!
はい、最後はですね、ちょっとあの、フブライは1匹だったんですけど、なんかスコン部がやたら多かったんですけども！一緒にですね、白上バンド曲がすごく大好きなので、こちらの桜のあと、歌わせていただきました！
And finally, even though there was only one of me, there was a whole bunch of Sukonbu back there! Since I love full-band songs, I sang 'Sakura no Ato' with them!
本当にありがとうございます！めちゃめちゃ楽しかったです！
Thank you so much! It was incredibly fun!
はい、そして、ここからは？
Alright, and what's next?
ここからは、それぞれが1期生のイメージに合う楽曲を1曲チョイスして、全員で歌う、プロデュース曲パートです！
From here on, it's the Produce Song Segment, where each of us has chosen a song that matches the image of the 1st Generation, and we'll all sing them together!
みんな、どんな曲選んだのか、めちゃめちゃ楽しみですね！
I'm so excited to find out what kind of songs everyone chose!
まあ、まつりはね、まあ王道かなって曲を選んだんですけど...
Well, as for me, I chose a song that's pretty mainstream...
はあちゃまはどんな曲？
What about Haachama's song?
はあちゃまは、可愛い！可愛くて、おなかよしな曲にしました！
Haachama chose a cute one! A cute and friendly song!
アキロゼはね、今時感もありつつ、ちょっとダークなみたいな！そういう一面もあるんじゃないかな、みたいな！
AkiRoze went with something that has a modern feel, but with a slightly dark edge! Showing another side of us!
フブキちゃんは？
And Fubuki-chan?
白上はですね、1期生だからこそ染みる曲！
For Shirakami, it's a song that hits deep precisely because we're the 1st Generation!
ということでですね、皆さんもね、コメントなどで予想して、何が来るかなーとお楽しみに！
So, everyone, feel free to leave your guesses in the comments and look forward to what's coming up!
じゃあ行きましょう、皆さん！それでは、グループパート、せーの...
Alright, let's do this, everyone! Here we go with the group segment, one, two...
スタート！
Start!
好き嫌いかの二者択一 どちらかと言えば好きでした
A choice between love and hate—if I had to choose, I loved it.
乗りかかった舟 止めちゃうほど 落ちぶれていないよ わかるでしょ
I'm not so washed up that I'd stop a boat I've already boarded, you know that.
不測不慮の事態も結構です こちら取って置きの続き人生(ライフ)だし<
Unexpected emergencies are perfectly fine; after all, I'm on a saved-up continuation of life.
行き先なんて二の次なんです
The destination is secondary.
聴こえてるでしょ
You can hear it, right?
アクセルしか踏まないよ
I'll only step on the gas!
止まり方なんて必要ない
No need to know how to stop!
涙もエンタメになる カメラ止めんなよ
Even tears will become entertainment, don't stop the camera!
ハイチーズ
Say cheese!
不甲斐ない私でもずっと 歩いてきた道がある
Even for my helpless self, there's a path I've walked down all this time.
つまり どうでもいいことなど何もなかったんだよ
In other words, nothing was ever completely pointless!
私混乱上昇いつだって ここが最前線さ
My confusion is rising, but this is always the front line!
最後まで目を離さないで
Don't take your eyes off me until the very end!
そりゃ私だって悩みのひとつやふたつはありますよ
Of course, even I have a worry or two.
眠れない夜の旅 彷徨う
Roaming on a journey through sleepless nights.
選択肢はストップ
My choices are put on hold.
バックアップなんてしたくないよ オートセーブ切って挑むからリアルなんだ
I don't want a backup, it's real because I turn off auto-save and challenge it.
緊張も鼓動に変える 瞬きすんなよ
Changing my nervousness into a heartbeat, don't blink!
おー！
Oh!
変わんない私だからきっと 繋いできた夢がある
Because I'm a self that doesn't change, there's surely a dream we've connected.
つまり どうでもいいことなど何もなかったんだよ
In other words, nothing was ever completely pointless!
私逆境上昇いつだって 現在が最高潮さ
My adversity is rising, but right now is always the climax!
最後まで手を離さないで
Don't let go of my hand until the very end!
普通じゃなくて
It's not ordinary,
特別じゃない
and it's not special.
代わりのいない
But because it's us,
僕らだから
who cannot be replaced,
止まない雨を
the endless rain,
明けない夜を
the night that never ends,
癒える傷を
and the healing wounds,
超えたんでしょ
we've overcome them all, haven't we?
不甲斐ない私でもずっと 歩いてきた道がある
Even for my helpless self, there's a path I've walked down all this time.
つまり どうでもいいことなど何もなかったんだよ
In other words, nothing was ever completely pointless!
私混乱上昇いつだって ここが最前線さ
My confusion is rising, but this is always the front line!
最後まで目を離さないで
Don't take your eyes off me until the very end!
最後まで私負けないから
Because I won't lose until the very end!
出会った日のきらめき
The sparkle of the day we met,
飾ってた偽りも
even the decorated falsehoods,
フトバレた憧れも
and the suddenly revealed aspirations,
カメラ止めんなよ
don't stop the camera!
から回ったエネルギー
My spinning energy,
輝くこのステージで
on this shining stage,
重なる物語
our overlapping stories,
瞬きすんなよ
don't blink!
したいから！ したいなら！ したいとき！ したいでしょ？
Because I want to! If you want to! When you want to! You want to, right?
いっしょに！
Together!
はい！
Yes!
わたしたちはここにいます ここには夢がちゃんとある
We are right here! Our dreams are definitely here!
フレンドならともだちでしょ
If we're friends, we're buddies, right?
そうだ！
Exactly!
「すき」って言ってみた
I tried saying "I love you."
だいすき！
I love you so much!
放課後なら当たり前のこと さあさ集まれ
After school is just business as usual, so come on, gather up!
こっそり帰るな 部活動だね 活動しちゃうね
Don't sneak off home, this is a club activity! We're totally active!
遊んでるんじゃありません
We're not just playing around!
「ただいま」ってあの子が言うよ
She says, "I'm home!"
おかえりー！
Welcome back!
みんなでいれば大丈夫
If we're all together, we'll be fine!
部！ エビバディセイ！ ともだちでいよーね！
Club! Everybody say! Let's be friends!
したいから！ したいなら！ したいとき！ したいでしょ？
Because I want to! If you want to! When you want to! You want to, right?
だいすき！
I love you!
はい！
Yes!
わたしたちは楽しんでる 24時間はしゃいでる
We are having fun, frolicking 24 hours a day!
屋上に真っ赤な太陽 かなり叫んでみた
Shouting to the bright red sun on the rooftop!
元気でーす！
I'm doing great!
わたしたちはここにいます ここには夢がちゃんとある
We are right here! Our dreams are definitely here!
フレンドならともだちでしょ
If we're friends, we're buddies, right?
そうだ！
Exactly!
「すき」って言ってみた
I tried saying "I love you."
だいすき！
I love you so much!
キーンコーンカーンコーンからの下校タイム
Ding-dong-dang-dong, and now it's home time!
「いいえ、わたしたち まだ帰りません」
"No, we're not going home yet!"
部活動だよ 活躍しちゃうよ
It's a club activity, we're gonna shine!
新入部員 募集中！
New members wanted!
「ごめんね」って小さく言うよ保存するね
I'll say "I'm sorry" in a quiet voice.
ケンカするほどほにゃららら？
The more we fight, the closer we are...?
ネバーギブアップ 最強になれるね
Never give up, we can become the strongest!
したいから！ したいなら！ したいとき！ したいでしょ？
Because I want to! If you want to! When you want to! You want to, right?
いっしょに！
Together!
はい！
Yes!
わたしたちは経験する 食べて眠って賢くなる
We are learning by experience, eating, sleeping, and getting smarter!
校庭に涼風吹いて 大きく手を振る
A cool breeze blows in the schoolyard, we wave our hands wide!
また明日ねー！
See you tomorrow!
わたしたちはここにいます ここには夢がちゃんとある
We are right here! Our dreams are definitely here!
フレンドなら ともだちでしょ
If we're friends, we're buddies, right?
そうだ！
That's right!
「すき」って言ってみた
I tried saying "I love you"
すき！
Love!
みんながここに集まれば
If everyone gathers here
がっこうは特別になる
School becomes something special
今日が終わっても明日も
Even if today ends, tomorrow too
笑顔で会えるね
We can meet with a smile, right?
わたしたちはここにいます
We are right here
ここには夢がちゃんとある
Our dreams are surely right here
フレンドなら ともだちでしょ
If we're friends, we're buddies, right?
だいすき ありがとっ！
I love you, thank you!
どうしてすぐ知ってしまうの
Why do you find out right away?
共振で苦しんで罵倒
Suffering and cursing in resonance
Q.更新で降る隕石抹消可？
Q. Can falling meteors be erased with an update?
悪くない
Not bad
興味ねえ救い派手感動
No interest in being saved, flashy emotions
常識ねえ薬食べ BAD
No common sense, eating pills and having a BAD trip
Q.超酷えフル見た目暗号化？
Q. Is the terrible, full appearance encrypted?
金に頼る
Relying on money
常識ねえ狂いいっぱいで乱闘
No common sense, a brawl full of madness
放置ゲーする陰キャでバンド
An introverted band playing idle games
Q.送信で苦しいダメ Cancel は？
Q. Sending is painful, can we cancel it?
草生える
LMAO
どうしてすぐ見てしまうの
Why do you look right away?
どうしてすぐ言ってしまうの
Why do you say it right away?
どうしてすぐ壊れちゃうかな
Why does it break so easily?
(パパラ パラ パラ)
(Papara para para)
近未来しか勝たん
The near-future is the only winner
ショッピングモールの現代コンピュー
Modern computer in a shopping mall...
小窓 死か加担
A small window, death or complicity
モンティホールの経費でピンボール
Pinball on the Monty Hall budget
オイルマッサージ100分コース足湯付き
100-minute oil massage with a foot bath
柚子を添えて
Garnished with yuzu
テテテテテトテテテテテト
Te-te-te-te-te-to te-te-te-te-te-to
テテテテト テテテテト テテテテトリス
Te-te-te-te-to te-te-te-te-to te-te-te-Tetris
どうしてこんな目に に に
Why does this happen to me, me, me?
興味がないこと 本気じゃないもの
Uninteresting things, half-hearted things,
全部後回しで
I put them all on the back burner
知ってることは知らんぷり
Pretending not to know what I know
私は終わってる
I'm so hopeless
恥ずかしい過去 知ってる奴らの
Those who know my embarrassing past,
記憶 消去させて
let me erase their memories
迷惑かけてごめんってば
I'm sorry for causing trouble!
ねぇ誰か助けて
Hey, somebody help me
妄信ですぐ引かれちゃうの
Blind faith gets me turned off right away
狂信ですぐ引かれちゃうの
Fanaticism gets me turned off right away
知りたくない知りたくない知りたくない
I don't wanna know, I don't wanna know, I don't wanna know
(タタラ タラ タラ)
(Tatara tara tara)
もう見ねえすぐ引かれ SAD
I won't look anymore, turned off and SAD
常識ねえ狂い立て MAD
No common sense, driven MAD
行きたくない行きたくない行きたくない
I don't wanna go, I don't wanna go, I don't wanna go
ばーいばい
Byebye
臨時休業 洗濯ボール
Temporary closure, laundry balls
ナイチンゲールの配信ゲーム
Nightingale's streaming game
名刺交換の名シーン
The famous business card exchange scene
借金ボウルでチンチロハイボール
Chinchiro highball with a debt bowl
温泉旅行3泊4日食事付き
Hot spring trip, 4 days and 3 nights with meals included
早く行きてえ
I wanna go soon!
テテテテテトテテテテテト
Te-te-te-te-te-to te-te-te-te-te-to
テテテテト テテテテト テテテテトリス
Te-te-te-te-to te-te-te-te-to te-te-te-Tetris
共感性羞恥 ち ち
Secondhand embarrassment, -ment, -ment
あっちとかそっちとか 忙しくて
Busy with this and that,
眠れないわ今日も
I can't sleep today either
誰か早く殴って
Someone, hit me quickly
気絶させてくれよ
and knock me out
人生キャンセル キャンセル界隈
Life cancel, the canceling community,
ぼんやりとした不安
a vague sense of anxiety
私のせい 私が悪いよ
It's my fault, I'm to blame,
そうだよ
that's right
興味が出ても 本気でやっても
Even if I'm interested, even if I try my best,
全部空回りで
it's all in vain
知らないくせに 嘘つき
You don't even know, liar,
私は終わってる
I'm so hopeless
恥ずかしい過去 知ってる奴らの
Those who know my embarrassing past,
記憶 消去させて
let me erase their memories
迷惑かけてごめんってば
I'm sorry for causing trouble!
ねぇ誰か助けて
Hey, somebody help me
迷惑かけてごめんってば
I'm sorry for causing trouble!
ねぇ誰か許して
Hey, somebody forgive me
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please don't ever stop being an idol
ずっと
(Forever)
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining
もう ずっとずっとずっと
Forever and ever and ever...
ステージにいて
...please stay on the stage
私がもし君のとこ 離れたなら
If I ever leave your side,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
will you feel a little lonely?
いじわる 考える
I mischievously think to myself
好きな人がいるのなら 内緒にして ねえ
If you have someone you love, keep it a secret, okay?
ねえ 神様は 将来と指輪を
Hey, God, please hide the future and the ring...
全てを知っている 私が言う
I, who know everything about you, tell you:
絶対空で輝いて
Never stop shining in the sky...
(ずっと)
...forever.
星は街じゃ輝かないの
Stars don't shine as brightly in the city.
眩しい君が世界一だよ
Dazzling as you are, you are the best in the world!
Wow, wow...
Wow, wow... Yeah!
君の夢は
What is your dream?
何ですか？ 教えて欲しい
Please tell me what it is.
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても
Even if that dream isn't to be an idol,
覚悟はしてるから
I'm prepared for that.
星のいない空
A sky without stars...
それが当たり前で
We took that for granted.
暗い道に目が慣れずに
My eyes couldn't adapt to the dark road,
踏み出すのも怖かった
and I was too afraid to take a step.
そんな時
Just then,
やっと見えた光
I finally saw the light...
絶対君は歌っていて
You must absolutely keep singing...
(ずっと)
...forever.
ただのエゴと分かっていても
Even if I know it's just my own selfishness,
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
those sparkling outfits suit you so well.
絶対大きなステージで
On an absolutely grand stage...
(ずっと)
...forever,
一列目でも前で感じたい
even from the front row, I want to feel it.
今日の歌い方 なんか好きだな
I really like the way you sang today.
君の努力 私の愛
Your effort, my love...
成り立つこの関係は
This relationship we've built...
強くて脆いの
is strong yet so fragile.
星の幸せ願ってた
I wished for my star's happiness,
だけど
but...
でも
But...
でもね
But, you know...
だって君はアイドルよ
Because you are an idol...
(ずっと)
...forever.
初めて目が合った日から
From the very first day our eyes met,
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
today and tomorrow, I only think of you.
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Absolutely never stop being an idol...
(ずっと)
...forever.
これは報われないおとぎ話
This is a fairytale with no reward.
恋よりももっと好きだ
I love you even more than a simple crush.
魔法よどうか解けないままで
Please, magic, never wear off...
Wow, wow...
Wow, wow... Yeah!
Yeah! Hoo!
はい！ということで！
All right! And with that...
プロドゥ... プロデュース曲1曲目でした！
The first produced song has concluded!
プロデュースでした！
It was indeed!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
どうでしたか？
What did you think?
ということで、じゃあちょっと...
With that said, let's...
えー、選曲1曲目は、まずキラーでございました！
Our first song choice was a real killer tune!
いい曲だった！
It was such a great song!
いや、めっちゃいい曲なの！めっちゃちょっとね、激しいダンスだったと思うんですけども
Yes, it's such a great song! Although the choreography was pretty intense,
いや、もうなんか...
well, you know...
本当にこの曲聞いて、絶対1期生これだろうっていう
when I heard this song, I felt it absolutely suited 1st Gen,
ね、思いながら、ちょっと歌詞分けとかもね、させていただいたんですけども
so that's how I thought about dividing up the lyrics, too.
もう本当...
I mean, really...
初めて聞いて
When I heard it for the first time,
染みた！
it really touched my heart!
染みるっしょ！そう！
It does, right? Exactly!
染みたよ！
It really touched me!
そう！もう、我々は常に最前線ということで
Yes! Because we are always on the front line!
いや、もうね、1期生、これからも頑張っていこう。最後まで目を離すんじゃないぞ！
So let's keep working hard, 1st Gen. Don't take your eyes off us till the end!
離さないよ！留める、留めるのよ！
We won't! Keep watching, keep watching!
そして、そして、次が...
And then, next is...
はい、アキロゼの...
Yes, Aki Rose's...
テトリスをやらせていただきました！テ、テ、テ、テトリス！
I was allowed to perform Tetris! Te-te-te-Tetris!
いや、これはね、可愛かったから、いつかちょっとみんなでやってみたいなって思ったの。
Well, it was so cute, so I always thought I'd like to try doing it with everyone.
ね、グループの、結構フォーメーションとかを、ぐるぐるした、な、な、な...
And we did some spinning formations as a group, like, s-s-spinning...
ちょっと難しかったけども
It was a bit difficult, though.
そう、それでちょっと頑張ってもらっちゃった。
Yeah, so I had everyone work really hard on it.
みんな、表情がやばかった！あはは！
Everyone's expressions were crazy! Ahaha!
なんかね...
Like, you know...
ちょっとね、必死だったけども
We were a bit desperate, though.
なんか我々はだいぶムスッとした感じが...
It felt like we had rather grumpy expressions...
まあ、そんな一面もね、愛してよ、ということで！
Well, love us even with that side, okay!
はい、お願いします！そして...
Yes, please! And then...
はい、そしてはあちゃまはフレンドしたい、フレンドしたかった！
Yes, and Haachama wanted to make friends, wanted to make friends!
というわけで、選びました！
And so, I chose that song!
あの、後ろの映像でね、思い出アルバム、みんな気づいた？
Did everyone notice the memory album in the background video?
気づいた！よかった、盛りだくさんで！
We noticed! Good, it was packed with memories!
思い出がいっぱい流れました！
So many memories played there!
まだ終わってないですけどね！
Though it's not over yet!
はい、そしてまつりちゃん！
Yes, and next, Matsuri-chan!
まつり、最後に絶対アイドル辞めないで！いや、これはね...
Matsuri, lastly, 'Zettai Idol Yamenai de'! Well, this...
まあ、まつりのエゴだったとしても、みんなにはアイドルでいちゃんとしてほしいなっていう気持ちで
Even if it's just Matsuri's selfishness, I wanted everyone to stay proper idols, with that feeling,
選ばせていただきましたよ！
I chose this song!
この曲もなんか1期生でやると、やっぱ染みたね！
Doing this song with 1st Gen really touched our hearts, didn't it?
確かに！染みる！
For sure! It hits hard!
やっぱ、7年目だから...
After all, we're in our 7th year...
ね！
Right!
すごく良かったです。
It was really great.
お、そして、このパートが終わったということは？
Oh, and now that this part is over, that means...
じゃあそろそろ、ハッシュタグの秘密を教えちゃおうかな。
Then, should I finally share the secret of the hashtag?
なんと、このハッシュタグなんですが、
Believe it or not, this hashtag is actually...
新曲のタイトルになってます！
...the title of our new song!
新曲！？
A new song?!
ということは、タイトルは、
That means the title is...
電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言？
"Cyber Pure Oshi Grand Declaration"?
そう！
Yes!
え、これは一体、どんな曲なんだ？
Eh? I wonder what kind of song this is.
一体どんな感じなんだろうな。
I wonder what it's like.
楽しみ！いや、ドキドキでございますけれども、
I'm looking forward to it! It's so exciting!
ぴゅあ推し大宣言ってことは、なんかみんなの曲ってことかな？
"Pure Oshi Grand Declaration" means it's a song for everyone?
ファンの、みんなの曲？
Like, a song for all the fans?
そういうことか！
That's it!
推してくれてるよな！
You are supporting us, right?!
推してくれてるよな！っていう曲なのか？
Is it a song that asks, "You are supporting us, right?!"
そう。
Exactly.
みんな、この配信を見てくれているみんなが、
Everyone, everyone watching this stream,
私たちのこと、
...you support us...
推し、だよね？
...as your "oshi", right?
まさか、他の人に、
You're not looking...
よそ見、なんかしてないよね？
...at anyone else, right?
四六時中、私たちのことを、
You're thinking about us...
考えてるよね？
...24/7, right?
1期生が推しだって、宣言してくれるよな？
You'll declare that the 1st Generation is your oshi, right?!
と言うことで、それでは聴いてください。1期生の新曲、せーの、
With that, please listen to it. The 1st Generation's new song, ready, set,
電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言！
Cyber Pure Oshi Grand Declaration!
はーい、これから配信始めるよ！みんな見てる？
Yes! We're starting our stream now! Is everyone watching?
今回はコラボ配信！
Today is a collab stream!
あれ？あれれ？コメントの熱量、なんだか少なくない？
Huh? Wait a minute. Isn't the comment section a bit too quiet?
まだまだ足りない！こんなの、
Not enough, not enough at all! Like this,
やだー！
No way!
このこのこの
This, this, this...
このこのこのこの！
This, this, this, this!
推し変は許しませんっ！
Changing your oshi is not allowed!
わたしだけに尽くしてね？
Devote yourself only to me, okay?
わたしだけに一途
Be single-minded only for me,
単推しじゃなきゃヤダヤダ、拗ねちゃうぜ
I hate it if you don't pick me as your sole favorite! I'll pout!
他の子になびいちゃヤダヤダ、でもね
Don't drift towards other girls! But wait,
よそ見をしたらぷんぷんぷんっ！めっ！
If you look away, I'll get really mad! Bad!
めらめらメンヘラップ、ほっぺ膨ら
Burning psycho-rap, cheeks puffed up,
にらめっこしましょ、あっぷっぷー、ぷいっ！
Let's have a staring contest! Don't laugh, hmph!
ぷくっと顔が可愛いでしょ？
My puffed-up face is cute, isn't it?
目移りはダメ！ほんとイヤ、イヤ
No eyeing others! I really, really hate it!
いつも見てて、見てて、わたし待ってる
Always watch me, watch me, I am waiting!
あなたが愛してくれる、愛ちゃんの全ツッパ
The full stakes of the love you give me,
わたしを支える栄養素
...are the nutrients that sustain me!
（LOVE YOU、LOVE YOU、LOVE YOU、四六時中チュッチュッ）
(LOVE YOU, LOVE YOU, LOVE YOU, thinking of you 24/7)
ねぇ、とっても、とっても、とっても、とっても、とっても、愛してほしい
Hey, I want you to love me so, so, so, so, so much!
（HAPPY、HAPPY、HAPPYが最上級）
(With top-tier HAPPY, HAPPY, HAPPY)
ほら、やっぱり、やっぱり、やっぱり、やっぱり、はっきり、はっきり、はっきり、はっきり
See, as expected, clearly, clearly,
（推して、推して）
(Oshi me, oshi me!)
（ピュアピュアに 振り切って）
(Go pure all the way!)
ぴこぴこ、キモチのバロメーターも超上がる
The piko-piko gauge of my feelings rises super high!
（単推し、神推し、■推し）
(Sole favorite, god favorite, blacked-out favorite)
もうほんとに、ほんとに、ほんとに、ほんとに、わかってね！
Really, really, really, really, make sure you understand!
おーい、みんな、ここまでついて来れてる？
Hey everyone, can you keep up so far?
この後も、この調子で行くよ！
Let's keep going like this!
うりゃおい！うりゃおい！うりゃおい！うりゃおい！うりゃおい！うりゃおい！
Uryaoi! Uryaoi! Uryaoi! Uryaoi! Uryaoi! Uryaoi!
ちょ待って、なんで他の子褒めるの？
Wait a minute, why are you praising other girls?
（よそ見疑惑発令中）
(Looking-away suspicion alert triggered!)
わたし以外も気になってるでしょ？
You're interested in someone other than me, aren't you?
ありえないよ、ありえない！
Unbelievable, totally unbelievable!
ぷんぷん、他の子にちょちょちょ、ちょっとだけ
Pout pout, did you look at other girls,
よそ見したよね？うぜマジ無理ですDEATH
...just a little bit? Seriously annoying, unacceptable, DEATH!
ピュア推し信者、わたし推すんじゃ！指切りしてよ、ハリセンボンっ！
Pure oshi believers, support me! Pinky swear, a thousand needles!
（ハリセンボンっ！×1000）
(A thousand needles! x1000)
心変わりしたらほんとに、拗ねる、怒る、泣いちゃうからね！
If you change your mind, I'll really pout, get angry, and cry, you hear?!
推し変はしてないね？
You haven't changed your oshi, right?
わたしだけに尽くしてる！
Devote yourself only to me!
だって、ほら、コメントが愛に溢れている！
Because, see, the comments are full of love!
瀕死のHP、みるみる回復
My dying HP is recovering rapidly!
チート級レベルな、パワーチャージ！
A cheat-tier level power charge!
ごめん、ごめん、ごめちょ、ごめん、ごめん、ごめん、ごめちょ！
Sorry, sorry, so sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, so sorry!
（LOVE YOU、LOVE YOU、LOVE YOU、四六時中チュッチュッ）
(LOVE YOU, LOVE YOU, LOVE YOU, thinking of you 24/7)
ねぇ、いっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱい、愛してほしい
Hey, I want you to love me so, so, so, so, so much!
（HAPPY、HAPPY、HAPPYが最上級）
(With top-tier HAPPY, HAPPY, HAPPY)
もう、うっとり、うっとり、うっとり、うっとり、にっこり、にっこり、にっこり、にっこり
Ah, spellbound, spellbound, with a smile, a smile,
（推して、推して）
(Oshi me, oshi me!)
わたしのため、日々、日々、推し事、励んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for working hard on your "oshi duties" for me every single day!
（ピュアピュアに ひたむきに）
(With pure and single-minded devotion!)
（単推し、神推し、■推し）
(Sole favorite, god favorite, blacked-out favorite)
そう、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい、ぜったい
Yes, absolutely, absolutely, absolutely, absolutely, absolutely...
お願いね！！！
...please do!!!
この、この、この、この！
This, this, this, this!
この、この、この、この、この、この！
This, this, this, this, this, this!
この、この、この、このーーー！！！
This, this, this, this...!!!
銀河の果てまで愛してほしい！
I want you to love me to the ends of the galaxy!
わーーー！！！
Wahhh!!!
ということで新曲でしたー！
And that was our new song!
いえーい！
Yay!
可愛い曲だったね。
That was such a cute song.
めちゃくちゃ可愛いし、なんかね、もう「推し！」って感じで、
It's super cute, and it's like, really "Oshi!"-themed.
みんなにもね、
I hope everyone...
ぜひ歌ったり踊ったり、いっぱい楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいなっていう1曲になってるんだけど、どうだった？
...can sing, dance, and enjoy this song as much as possible! What did you think?
いやー、もうやっぱり、楽しいね、この曲ね！
Ah, it's really fun, this song!
楽しかった！まさしく白上のド趣味な曲、作ってくれた、な感じなんだけど、
It was fun! It really feels like they made a song that perfectly fits Shirakami's tastes.
なんか今回、
Also, this time...
この曲聞いたときに、
When I heard this song,
「これ、これちょっとまつりちゃんにね、ちょっと頑張ってもらうかな」ってところで。
I thought, "This is where we should have Matsuri-chan do her best."
セリフのところとか、ちょっとまつりちゃんに。
So I gave the dialogue parts to Matsuri-chan.
この歌の。
In this song.
そう、歌詞分けをフブキが。
Yes, Fubuki did the lyric distribution.
なんかちょっと決めっぽいところはまつりちゃんかなと思って。
I thought the punchy parts should go to Matsuri-chan.
あそこ、みんなよく噛まなかったね。
No one tripped over their words in that part.
偉かった！
We did so well!
あと、アキロゼセクシーだったね。
Also, Akirose was so sexy.
あ、良かった。
Oh, thank goodness.
良かったね、ここ好き、ペン、ペンってね。
That's great. I love this part, "pen-pen," right?
お尻叩いて。めっちゃ可愛かった。
Smacking the butt. It was so cute.
まつりちゃんに銃で撃たれてた時。
And when Matsuri-chan shot us with a gun.
バン！
Bang!
これ、可愛かったですね。
That was so cute.
はい、そんな。この曲は？
Yes, indeed. And what about this song?
この曲が。おっ？
This song is... Oh?
おっと？21時15分から？
Wait? Starting at 21:15...
こちらの公式チャンネルで。
On this official channel,
先ほど歌わせていただきました新曲「電脳ぴあ推し大宣言」のMVが出ちゃいます！
the MV for our new song "Cyber Peer-Oshi Grand Declaration" will be released!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い映像になってますので、ぜひそちらもチェックしてくださいね！
The video is incredibly cute, so please check it out too!
さて、ではここからは告知タイムです！
Now, from here on, it's announcement time!
今回のグッズは「hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade」！
Today's merchandise is the "hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade"!
こちら5月30日からカートオープンされてます！
The cart has been open since May 30th!
はい、皆さんチェックしてくれてるとは思いますが、内容を見てみましょう！
Yes, I'm sure you've already checked it, but let's look at the details!
どれどれどれ。
Let's see, let's see.
はい、まずキービジュアルは、おっとん先生に描いていただきました！
First, the key visual was illustrated by Otton-sensei!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今年のホロ全体での期生周年グッズのテーマは「パレード」！
This year's overall Hololive generation anniversary theme is "Parade"!
その中でも、我々1期生はマーチングバンドです！
Among them, we, the 1st Generation, are a marching band!
ではでは、1個ずつグッズを見ていきましょうかね。こちら！
So, let's look at each item one by one. Here it is!
まずはですね、プレミアムアクリル色紙！
First up is the Premium Acrylic Art Board!
こちら複製サインとロゴが箔押しで入ってます！よろしくおねがいします。
It features hot-stamped duplicated signatures and the logo! Please look forward to it.
そして、続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
オフィシャルホロカスリーブ！アニバーサリーパレード1期生バージョン！
Official Holo-Card Sleeve, Anniversary Parade 1st Gen Version!
60枚入りです。
It contains 60 sleeves.
ホロカードが入ります。
It fits Holo-Cards.
カードもスリーブも1期生で、染め上げてください。
Color your cards and sleeves with the 1st Generation.
そして、次は、こちら！
And next up is this!
お、まつりちゃん、言ってもらおうかな？
Oh, Matsuri-chan, would you like to announce this?
はい！アクリルスタンド！
Yes! Acrylic Stand!
今回のキービジュアルの衣装がアクリルスタンドになりました。
The outfits from the key visual are now acrylic stands.
なんと、プレミアムアクリル色紙に比べて、それぞれ表情が異なっちゃいますよ。
Believe it or not, they have different facial expressions compared to the Premium Acrylic Art Board.
ああ、いい。集めたくなっちゃう。
Oh, nice. It makes you want to collect them all.
はい、こんな感じですね。
Yes, just like this.
そして最後はアキロゼ！
And finally, Akirose!
はい、なんと記念メダル出ちゃいます！
Yes, we are releasing Commemorative Medals!
はい、こちらはなんと、ケースと巾着がついて豪華な仕様になっておりまして、
Yes, this is a deluxe version that comes with a case and a drawstring pouch,
期生ごとにね、デザインが異なっているので、ぜひぜひコレクションしたくなっちゃうアイテムなんじゃないのかなと思っています。
with different designs for each generation, making it a highly collectible item.
タレントカラーと名前も入っているので、ぜひゲットしてね！
They feature the talents' colors and names, so please get yours!
お願いします。
Please do!
そして、こちらのグッズなんですが、受注期間が、えっと5月30日金曜日から
And for these items, the order period is from Friday, May 30th,
今月6月30日月曜日までなので、皆さん忘れずにご購入してください！
until Monday, June 30th of this month, so don't forget to purchase!
以上、周年のグッズ告知でした！
That's all for the anniversary merchandise announcements!
次はメンバー個別の告知タイムです！
Next is the announcement time for individual members!
1つずつ、まつりちゃんから！
One by one, starting with Matsuri-chan!
はい！じゃあまつりは周年グッズの告知にしますよ。
Yes! I will announce my anniversary merchandise.
はい、ということで、このあとですね、21時30分から、まつりの個人の周年グッズが出ちゃいますので、
Yes, so after this, starting at 21:30, my personal anniversary merchandise will be released,
ぜひぜひ買ってください。超可愛いイラストです。そして、はあとちゃん！
so please buy them. The illustrations are super cute. Next, Haato-chan!
はい、はあちゃまはこちら！ドドン！
Yes, Haachama is here! Ta-da!
めちゃゴミ・完・全・食！
"Mecha Gomi Complete Feast"!
本日の24時から、各種配信サービスでもリリースされるので、お楽しみに！6周年グッズも、あります！明日ですよ！
It will be released on various streaming services starting at 24:00 today, so please look forward to it! There are also 6th anniversary goods! It's tomorrow!
6周年？
6th anniversary?
8周年、あ、間違えた！
8th... Ah, I made a mistake!
7！7！7周年グッズも、
7! 7! My 7th anniversary goods are also...
お楽しみに！
look forward to them!
お楽しみに、という形になっております！はい！
Please look forward to them! Yes!
はい、白上です！白上もですね、グッズが出るんですけども、
Yes, I'm Shirakami! I'm also releasing some goods,
こちらですね、6月3日に発売予定でございます！
which are scheduled to go on sale on June 3rd!
うわああああ！
Waaah!
グッズの詳細などはよければ6月3日の配信お楽しみに！
For more details on the goods, please look forward to the June 3rd stream!
お楽しみにー！
Please look forward to it!
そして、最後アキちゃん！
And finally, Aki-chan!
はい！はい、はい、はい、はい！
Yes! Yes, yes, yes, yes!
アキロゼのほうからも、なんと！
From AkiRose, guess what!
2024年かな？自分の生誕祭のときにお披露目しました
I think in 2024? Revealed during my birthday celebration...
ミュージカル「ブレーメン」の曲がついに配信になりました！
...the songs from the musical "Bremen" are finally released!
おおー！やったー！
Whoa! Yay!
このあと24時リリース予定なので
It's scheduled to be released at 24:00 tonight, so...
ぜひいっぱい聴いたり歌ってみたり踊ってみたりして楽しんでもらえたらなと思ってます！
I hope you listen to it a lot, sing along, dance, and enjoy it!
あと、ミュージックビデオとしてね、その...
Also, as a music video...
ミュージカル部分だけ切り取ったものも上げようと思っているので、アキロゼのチャンネルもぜひ見てください！
I'll upload just the musical parts, so please check out AkiRose's channel!
はーい！
Okay!
はい！以上告知タイムでしたー！
All right! That was all for the announcement time!
わーい！
Yay!
ということでですね、7周年迎えて...
So, having reached our 7th anniversary...
え？そう、8周年ですか、明日から？
Wait? Is it our 8th anniversary starting tomorrow?
あれ？早い！
Wait, really? That was fast!
ちょっと、そういうことは？あの、ちびっこに例えると、中学2年生！
Wait, what does that mean? If we compare it to kids, we're in our second year of junior high!
我々は中二だ！
We are chuunibyou (8th graders)!
中学2年生！中二になった！
Second-year junior high schoolers! We became 8th graders!
封印が解けるような...
Like a seal is being broken...
恥ずかしい、恥ずかしい！
So embarrassing, so embarrassing!
これ以上解き放たれたらまずい！
If we release any more power, it'll be bad!
まあね、これからも のんびりやっていく1期生でございますけれども
Well, we're the 1st generation who will continue to do things at our own pace...
これからも楽しく活動していきますので、みなさんよろしくお願いします！
...but we will keep having fun with our activities, so please continue to support us!
よろしくお願いします！
Please support us!
頑張ろうぜー！
Let's do our best!
はい、それではですね、またそれぞれの配信でお会いしましょう！
All right, then, we'll see you again in our respective streams!
せーの、ばいばーい！
Ready, go, bye-bye!